John Ericsson I. Robarios

Frontend Developer

Detail-oriented, analytical, and self-driven programmer with 2+ years experience developing user-facing applications. Efficient and knowledgeable coder with skills in HTML, JavaScript CSS, PHP, and Python programming languages and its current and Coordinated frameworks libraries. collaborative team player with attention to detail, graphic design skills, and ability to contribute to code base improvement initiatives and UX improvement projects.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

Hivelabs Technologies Corporation

03/2022 - Present

Caloocan City, MNL

- Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Used understanding of Vue and React fundamentals to promote better component lifecycle practices, increasing turnaround speed by 23% with 100% deadline adherence.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.

Unilever UCOIN

- Developed U-COIN's frontend, which is Unilever Philippines, Inc.'s unified digital rewards program to give treats to consumers across several channels.
- Implemented new responsive, mobile-first approach which increased mobile traffic by 20%.

PUDO Express

- Developed PUDO web admin, which manages orders from the local delivery app.
- Collaborated with iOS and Android developers to implement live order monitoring in web admin.

Calamian Travel and Tours

Developed Calamian Travel and Tours booking website that is integrated with the client's inhouse system.

Freelance Web Developer

UpWork

10/2020 -03/2022

Pasay City, MNL

Review Center LMS

Developed a learning management system for review centers that wants to operate during the pandemic.

EDUCATION

BSc in Aeronautical Engineering

Philippine State College of Aeronautics

07/2014-10/2020 Pasay City, MNL



ercsssn@gmail.com @

0927 928 1053 🛚

Pasay City, MNL •

www.linkedin.com/in/ercsssn in

https://github.com/ercsssn \(\O\)

https://ericrob.com



GENERAL SKILLS

Web Development Relational Databases Responsive Design **Test Driven Development Object Oriented Programming** Debugging Data Structures and Algorithms Machine Learning

TECHNICAL SKILLS



ESSENTIAL SKILLS

| Critical Thinking | Communication | Work Ethic |
|-------------------------------------|-----------------|--------------|
| Time Management Attention to Detail | | |
| Public Speaking | Problem-solving | Adaptability |

CERTIFICATES

Python 3 Programming

University of Michigan (Coursera) 11/2020 https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/ specialization/certificate/FRSDHKP4FU5X

Excel Skills for Business

Macquarie University (Coursera) 11/2020 https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/ specialization/certificate/VFZ3EKHAS226

Data Structures and Algorithms

UC SanDiego (Coursera) 04/2021 https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/ specialization/certificate/JCW9LQXRQDY6

AWS Fundamentals

Amazon Web Services (Coursera) 01/2021 https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/ specialization/certificate/74U7M9RGEGRT